{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Agarose gel electrophoresis and pulsed field gel electrophoresis may be used to resolve respectively", "opta": "2000 kb and 20kb DNA", "optb": "1000 kb and l0kb DNA", "optc": "20 kb and 2000 kb DNA", "optd": "10 kb and 1000 kb DNA", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The IPTG is a gratuitous inducers of (\u03b2-galactosidase, and x-gal is a chromogenic substrate. When \u03b1-complementation occurs which colour is produced?", "opta": "Blue", "optb": "White", "optc": "Brown", "optd": "No colour is produced", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The competitive immunoassay can be used", "opta": "to detect very small amounts of antigen", "optb": "to detect antibody associated with allergies (IgE)", "optc": "both (a) and (b)", "optd": "commonly to detect trace amounts of drugs.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an immunodiffusion test?", "opta": "Double-diffusion", "optb": "Gel diffusion", "optc": "Ouchterloney technique", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Counter immunoelectrophoresis", "opta": "electrophoresis will drive the antibody and antigen parallel to each other", "optb": "electrophoresis will drive the antibody and antigen toward each other", "optc": "the antibody will migrate towards anode", "optd": "the antibody will migrate towards cathode", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the ELISA test intended to measure?", "opta": "Antibody to HIV only", "optb": "Antigen to HIV only", "optc": "Presence of free, circulating virus in the patient", "optd": "Antibodies directed against HLA molecules", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Immunoaffinity chromatography can be used in biochemical applications to", "opta": "break down antibody structure", "optb": "purify protein antigen", "optc": "break down antigen and analyze quantitatively", "optd": "none of the above", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Different form of a plasmid, on an agarose gel, after electrophoresis may be in which of the following sequence in decreasing molecular weight?", "opta": "Open circular, super coiled, linear plasmid DNA", "optb": "Linear plasmid, open circular, super coiled plasmid", "optc": "Open circular, super coiled, linear plasmid DNA", "optd": "Open circular, linear plasmid, super coiled plasmid", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "In Rocket Immunodiffusion the length of the rocket is", "opta": "proportional to the amount of antibody placed in each well", "optb": "inversely proportional to the amount of antibody placed in each well", "optc": "inversely proportional to the amount of antigen placed in each well", "optd": "proportional to the amount of antigen placed in each well", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Radial Immunodiffusion is similar to", "opta": "double-diffusion", "optb": "gel diffusion", "optc": "Ouchterloney technique", "optd": "all of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Agarose a porous matrix used in various molecular biology technique is made by repetitive units of", "opta": "maltose", "optb": "agarobiose", "optc": "agar", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What radioactive molecule is used to end-label an oligonucleotide?", "opta": "(alpha)-32P-ATP", "optb": "(alpha)-32P-dUTP", "optc": "(gamma)-32P-ATP", "optd": "Any of these", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following radioactive element is generally involved in RIA?", "opta": "Tritium", "optb": "Carbon-14", "optc": "Iodine-125", "optd": "All of these", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is approximatively the half life of 32-Phosphorus?", "opta": "14 days", "optb": "28 days", "optc": "42 days", "optd": "30 days", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Rocket Immunodiffusion is also known as", "opta": "gel diffusion", "optb": "electroimmunodiffusion", "optc": "double-diffusion", "optd": "none of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "DNA- footprinting is a suitable technique for identifying which of the following?", "opta": "Particular mRNA in mixture", "optb": "Particular t-RNA in mixture", "optc": "Introns within DNA", "optd": "Protein binding site within DNA", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What would happen if serum is omitted from the ELISA, but all other steps remain same?", "opta": "Anti-human Ig-conjugate would not bind and be washed away", "optb": "The OD values would be nearly the same as the assay control", "optc": "Both (a) and (b)", "optd": "Anti-human Ig-conjugate would bind non-specifically to the ELISA plate", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "RAST test (radio allergosorbent test) is often used to detect", "opta": "antibodies associated with allergies (IgE)", "optb": "antigen associated with allergies (IgE)", "optc": "bacteriophages", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What would happen if the anti-human Ig-conjugate is not washed free of the well before the substrate is added?", "opta": "The ELISA would not develop when the substrate was added", "optb": "The ELISA would develop normally", "optc": "All wells would show uniform over-development due to unbound and excess anti-human Ig enzyme conjugate", "optd": "None of the above", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An antigen preparation and an antibody preparation are tested by immunodiffusion. Three bands are found, indicating that", "opta": "there was more than one antigen", "optb": "the antibody was impure", "optc": "the temperature was too high", "optd": "there was one antibody and one antigen", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Immunoelectrophoresis techniques are designed to separate the mixture components from each other by using electrophoresis", "opta": "prior to reaction with antibody", "optb": "prior to reaction with antigen", "optc": "after reaction with antibody", "optd": "after reaction with antigen", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is a positively charged matrix for ion exchange chromatography?", "opta": "CM cellulose", "optb": "DEAE cellulose", "optc": "Phosphocellulose", "optd": "None of these", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an immunoelectrophoresis technique?", "opta": "Two-dimensional immunoelectrophoresis", "optb": "Counterimmunoelectrophoresis", "optc": "Coimmunoelectrophoresis", "optd": "Both (a) and (b)", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}